African Cats is a documentary, adventure film directed by Keith Scholey.
African Cats captures the real-life love, humor and
determination of the majestic kings of the savanna.
The story features Mara, an endearing lion cub who strives to grow up with her mother’s strength, spirit and wisdom; Sita, a fearless cheetah and
single mother of five mischievous newborns; and Fang, a proud leader of the pride who must defend his family from a once banished lion.
Narrator (voice), played by Samuel L. Jackson.
Narrator (voice), played by Patrick Stewart.
African Cats (known as Felines in France) is a 2011 nature documentary film about a pride of lions and a family of
cheetahs trying to survive in the African savannah directed by Alastair Fothergill and Keith Scholey.
The film was released theatrically by Disneynature on Earth Day, April 22, 2011.
The film is narrated by Samuel L.
Jackson (Patrick Stewart in the UK release).
A portion of the proceeds for the film were donated to the African Wildlife
Foundation and their effort to preserve Kenya's Amboseli Wildlife Corridor.
The film's initiative with the African Wildlife Foundation is named "See African Cats, Save the
Savanna", and as of May 2011, ticket sales translated into 50,000 acres of land saved in Kenya.
The film explores themes of africa, lion, leopard, lion cub, wildlife.